35 Years FileMakering + 18 Claris Certifications + 2 Degrees in UI/UX + 1 Ad♦Q Award for Outstanding Readership Response =



+1 (513) 290-2217 • jeffdrake@drakeling.com

In 1989, my father started a side hustle doing FileMaker development for local clients, both supporting our family and bringing his teenage son along for the ride. Dad has long since retired, but his early influence led me to an unexpected career. 35 years later, the Claris platform has grown with leaps and bounds, and I've been with them every step of the way!

Selected Accomplishments



Apple: led development team for Project Solvang, an internal, hybrid FileMaker/HTML5 system to track hundreds of thousands of expenditures with budgets in the **tens of billions of dollars** per department.

• initiated comprehensive code review of server-side scripting; updated methods utilized to reduce processing time from 6½ hours to 17 seconds



National Gallery of Art: collaborated with personnel and project managers to assess requirements for new budget and requisitioning system

 secured budgets and approval functions per client needs, creating highly granular access privileges for different supervisory levels



MKS Building Systems: extended and redesigned existing system with iPad-specific interface and increased performance by up to 90%

- built HTML5 interface to automatically design floor plans and elevations (including support locations) based on requested dimensions
- added drag-and-drop functionality to allow users to locate specified options (e.g. doors, windows, etc.) on elevations
- integrated existing system with total station for high-precision GPS locations



Strong Systems: created **alarm management system for Chick-fil-A**, Dwarf House, and various local homes and businesses

• increased customer service efficiency by 90% with new, custom tracking application that properly identified false alarms and technical errors from internet-based reports

Selected Accomplishments (continued)



National Institute of Health: adapted software to new host and server versions, implementing emerging technologies

- rebuilt epilepsy trials database to allow integration of systems and reduced duplicate data entry by over 50%
- evaluated system performance and sought out opportunities to incorporate modern design elements



Building Automation Products, Inc.: constructed mobile application to serve relevant subsets of aged, **multimillion-record system**

• adapted FileMaker Go interface for proper functionality in Android-based WebDirect

Communication



- Native English speaker: born and raised in the United States of America
- Fluent Spanish speaker: studied American Spanish for six years, including an undergraduate major in Spanish; lived and worked in Spain for two years, becoming fluent in the Castilian dialect

Certifications



- Claris FileMaker Expert
- Claris FileMaker Specialist
- Claris FileMaker Associate
- Claris FileMaker Server Associate
- Claris Connect Associate
- Claris FileMaker Certified Developer
- FileMaker 18 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 17 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 16 Certified Developer

- FileMaker 15 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 14 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 13 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 12 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 11 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 10 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 9 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 8 Certified Developer
- FileMaker 7 Certified Developer

Languages, Frameworks, Skills



- JSON / RESTful APIs
- Amazon Web Services
- Microsoft Windows Server
- FileMaker Server
- SQL / Ms SQL Server
- MirrorSync
- FMPerception

- HTML5
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Cascading Style Sheets
- Tailwind CSS
- XML / XSLT
- Adobe CS and CC
- AppleScript

Employment History



Senior FileMaker Developer / Answers Desk Lead, MainSpring | 2021-2024

- employed Agile methodologies to manage project lifecycles, ensuring timely delivery
- first line of defense for customer support requests: addressed concerns and assigned repairs to most appropriate team member (including myself)
- managed clients' FileMaker servers and AWS hosting accounts
- mentored and assisted junior- and mid-level team members
- integrated various client systems with external APIs to eliminate duplication of efforts
- built custom sync process to migrate clients from commercial solutions to native functionality
- conducted technical workshops to share knowledge and best practices



FileMaker Developer, PaleoWest (now Chronicle Heritage) | 2020-2021

- created HTML5-based dashboard for company-wide snapshots and file access
- combined and standardized disparate databases into single, multi-file solution
- managed servers and files for frequent employee turnover and adding new projects



Senior Developer, Beezwax Datatools | 2020

- rescued severely overdue, over-budget project and secured customer loyalty
- engineered external system to transfer complete schema from corrupted custom app to fresh, new FileMaker solution



FileMaker Developer, Blue Feather (now Gearbox Solutions) | 2018-2019

- built, tested, and deployed scalable, highly available and modular FileMaker applications
- integrated FileMaker solutions with web services via third-party APIs and cURL commands
- managed clients' FileMaker, Active/Open Directory, SharePoint, and other network servers



Technical Lead, MKS Building Systems (now closed) | 2017-2018

- updated and optimized in-house applications, improving performance by over 90%
- enhanced building construction sales with HTML5-based, drag-and-drop elevations

Employment History (continued)



Senior Application Developer, Phototype (now Olberding Brand Family) | 2015-2017

- managed multiple database environments to ensure client confidentiality: competing clients were served by staff in different departments and buildings
- consolidated hundreds of scripts to reduce redundancy by up to 95%
- boosted productivity by creating compact (iPad-ready) replacements for oversized interfaces
- accelerated rollout procedures by instituting separation of concerns



Web / Applications Developer, HealthSouth (now Encompass Health) | 2015-2017

- optimized code to reduce server count by 50%.
- automated processes to increase employee efficiency
- averted critical loss by programming and instituting data backup procedures



Drakeling Technologies (sole proprietor) | 2003-2018

- analyzed user needs and workflows to create powerful solutions with easy-to-use interfaces
- Lead Developer for Excelisys, managing up to four concurrent projects, completing 18 total
- increased customer service efficiency by 90% using custom alarm-tracking applications
- eliminated publishing costs by digitizing encyclopedia, integrating FileMaker interface with SQL-based online access to over 40,000 terms and references



IT Specialist / Marketing Coordinator, S&S Fire Apparatus Co. (now closed) | 2002-2003

- enhanced employee productivity by normalizing database systems, preventing duplicate and contradictory data
- improved product quality and customer satisfaction by eliminating over 100 final production revisions through a customer photo-based feedback system
- maintained companywide internal network and Microsoft Windows servers, including software and hardware updates
- designed and published annual catalog encompassing 12 product lines
- received Ad-Q Award for Outstanding Readership Response: authored magazine advertisement that increased lead generation by 400%

Education



Purdue University

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Graphics Technology | 2001
- Associate of Science, Computer Graphics Technology | 2000